[Music] This is what
Kiryat Haim Beach looks like today. The sand has disappeared and is
drifting into the sea. The beach area has been reduced by 3 to 40 meters. What
was once a walking path for thousands of walkers has
become an obstacle course. This is one of my favorite beaches
with my family. As a child, I would come
here and
sit. Now there is nothing left. It is hard to see
this because other places could be developed like that, let
people live here, maybe make beaches. It is sad
to see that it is like this. About six months ago,
we exposed the problem here. The oil
and energy company, which was just building a new fence, was found to be
responsible for the disappearance of the sand. The state-owned company
was required to inject 70 meters of sand.
This was done, but today there is no trace of the sand that was there.
This is what is called a
predetermined death because even before they built the
Haifa wall, they determined that this is what would happen. There are reports. There are
documents that are written in black and white that this is what
would happen. Maher Hartner, an architect and expert in port planning,
says that the oil and energy company will not be
responsible for the disappearance of the sand naturally.  When a
breakwater of the type of the massive breakwater of Maale Ha'aleh is built, the coastal
bay is destroyed, the
Haifa seascape changes on one side, the polynom, a
naval anchorage, is built on the other side, the ant,
Ratner Bay, who saw the environmental impact before
the work even began, says that there was an
explicit warning of the retreat of the sand. I saw the
actual destruction of the sandy cliff that limits the land to an unbelievable extent.
Two and a half meters simply fell into the
sea and the damage is catastrophic. I predict that this year the
damage will also reach the shores of Qerai Yam and north. The Ministry of
Environmental Protection is monitoring the enormous damage and has already
scheduled an urgent meeting with all the parties
involved. There is no doubt that as a result of this construction, there are
changes in currents and increased noise on the shores of the bay. We
need to understand here. There is a complex of infrastructure here.
Each of them has a
marginal contribution, and together they make a very serious contribution.
We need to make sure that all the parties unite.
Hands and causes the sand or the packed sand to be blocked.
Meanwhile, the waves continue to bite more and more
parts of the beach, including a nearby business
whose perimeter fence was breached and large holes were dug. The
bathing season is still far away, but if steps are not taken
now, this coming summer there will be neither sand
nor a beach that is broken and without
forces, just like the beach. The company from Namla Israel said
in response that the port construction work has little effect
on the retreat of the sand. Despite this, the company has deposited 100
meters of sand on the beaches instead.